This video is an English subtitled version of this animation.
Please also support the official channel.
Brought to you by Guodong Subs
Translator: Sophia   First Proof: Nightcache   Second Proof: Cuchallain & Wuzimiko   QC: Raliath
Lyrics translator: Wuzimiko  Proofreader:  Ile, Serin & Nightcache   Timer/Effect/Encoder: KFC
It is now
year 4386 of the Cultivation Calendar.
'Tis the great era of Scientific Cultivation!
Look here, everyone!
It's a Level 1 Anti-Aging Pill!
From Talismans to Spiritual Artifacts, we have everything you need!
Eating it will nourish your beauty!
The 13th Spiritual Sword Competition (LIVE)
Men's Sword Finals (Individual)
Victory
Fight
The two contenders are going all out in their attacks!
They're not giving their rival any chance!
In the nation of Huaxiu, everyone cultivates.
Ticket Office    Information Desk
People enjoy a life of convenience brought by Scientific Cultivation.
As always,
people lived peacefully
until...
Alcohol
Look!
What is that?
Run!
An urgent newsflash!
Level 5 Demon King *Tuntian-ha has appeared in Songhai.
*Tuntian-ha, also known as the Sky-Swallowing Toad. A demon king.
The Cultivation Tactical Unit has been mobilized and is on their way.
Cultivation
Attention!
*Bullet comments that scroll across the screen.
*Danmu Flying Sword.
Fire!
Live News
Unidentified Object Invades Our City
Right on target!
In the face of such a tactical bombardment,
even the Demon King should go down, right?
Wait!
Tuntian-ha got up again.
Argh!
Disperse!
Ah!
Kid,
run!
Run!
Cough!
Ahh...
Kid,
are you alright?
Hurry back home to your parents.
I'm off to fight the monster.
This man, who went in alone and defeated Tuntian-ha,
was Zhuo Yi.
This battle made him famous,
and later generations called him
"The Hero who Saved Huaxiu".
Many Cultivation Sects
have a statue of him at their place.
The new cohort doesn't look all that promising.
It is
the first day of school for No. 60 Cultivation Academy.
Oh wow,
isn't she kinda cute?
New Students' Entrance Ranking
Huh?
Why is there someone with 5 Spiritual Points (SP)?
Isn't he too weak?
Mm?
*Shidi: A male junior in the same school. Xiao-shidi, meaning Little Shidi, is often used to address an underclassman.
*Xiao-shidi,
based on the picture, I guess you are that "SP-5" freshman?
Don't worry, Xiao-shidi,
*Shixiong: An honorific addressing a male senior, or in this case, an upperclassman.
your *shixiongs will take good care of you.
Thanks.
Huh?
Taking care of others is hard work, you know.
Surely you're not making your seniors work for free?
Right?
Hahahahaha!
That's right!
They're too much!
Wait.
Look!
You bully new students with low SP
simply because your SP is higher.
Not so cool, don't you think?
She looks so familiar.
Isn't she the legendary
Young Lady of the Huaguo Waterfall Association,
Sun Rong?
She just enrolled, yet she could already wield the Golden Light Beam?
Damn it!
Get down now!
Shixiongs,
I'm here.
What do you have for me?
Real men don't hit women!
Don't ever appear in front of me again!
Whenever, and wherever,
no matter what happens,
I,
Sun Rong,
promise to protect all of you.
Thank you.
You've worked hard.
Eh?
As per the academy's re-opening tradition,
an important
placement test will be held on this day.
We must do our best!
Yo!
New students of Stage 1,
hello!
Wow!
That's Zhuo Yi!
Cultivator Zhuo!
He's so cool...
Welcome to my alma mater.
All who just entered the academy
must undergo a mysterious Spiritual Aptitude Test.
Your results for this test
shall determine your classes.
High performers
will be assigned to the gifted class.
Do your best, everyone!
We will!
When you hear your number,
enter the gym from here, one by one.
Here,
on behalf of the Huaxiu Cultivation Council,
I wish everyone
the best of luck in Cultivation.
Spiritual Aptitude Test
Songhai No. 60 Cultivation Academy, Spiritual Aptitude Test
Ahem.
Student No. 001,
Ku Xuan,
please enter.
Here.
Who in the world is he?
(author of the original work)
I think he's an author whose work was made into some Donghua?
I may
have seen him on a magazine's cover.
Why is it so dark?
Huh? Water?
It's too dark to see.
What kind of test is this?
God...
Isn't that...?
To think that
we'd be fighting the Demon King who invaded the Mortal Realm ten years ago.
Tuntian-ha!
There is no need to worry though.
Notice
No work for this afternoon
Certificate of Honor
The real Tuntian-ha is still sealed underneath the campus.
This is just
the incarnation of its spiritual force.
Hit here
For your test,
please muster your spiritual force
and attack its head.
That's it.
From what I remember, high-level Demon Kings
can clearly measure the Spiritual Points of their attackers.
So long as I hit its head hard enough,
I'll make it into the gifted class!
That was really embarrassing.
An incarnation has intimidated me so?!
Watch me beat this toad to a pulp!
I'm the original author of this work!
What?!
*404: "404 Not Found", pun fully intended.
SP-404,
general class.
Looks like
the water on the ground
serves as a buffer for the ejected students.
Not because basketball courts are too hard to draw?
Even when sealed,
the Demon King still has a five figure SP.
Attacking it with the spiritual force of a freshman
is like throwing a ping-pong ball at a bowling ball.
It will definitely send you flying.
Is that how the academy intends to intimidate their freshmen?
(director of this donghua)
No. 002, Li Hao,
please enter.
Yah!
SP-75,
general class.
Quit the group chat!
Why are you even here?
Sigh.
Why is this cohort so awful?
There were students above 700 to 800 SP last year.
My opponent's the Demon King!
I'm all fired up!
Chen Chao,
SP-938,
gifted class.
Nice!
SP-528,
gifted class.
SP-331,
general class.
SP-201,
Guo Hao,
SP-886,
gifted class.
Hahahaha!
Do these foolish students
truly believe that I'm alright with the beating?
For ten years I have been sealed away.
No. 138,
Sun Rong.
Here!
It's Sun Rong!
Every year, when they use me as the measurement tool,
I get to absorb some spiritual power
from those youngsters.
Hmph!
With her SP,
she could have attended one of the top schools.
Why did she choose our academy?
Just a little more.
I will obtain enough Spiritual Force to
destroy this damn barrier today!
Wang Zukang!
Just you wait!
Oh my god, I can't believe that she's going to be my classmate!
Goddess!
This girl looks like
she has a high SP.
I'm sorry,
but I'm gonna punch you with my little fist.
Come on, hit me~
Croak croak.
Wow!
Oh my goodness.
Goddess!
S-Sun...
Sun Rong!
Goddess!
Calculating...
SP-
Goddess!
2019.
Thanks!
Thank you!
Eh?
Isn't he that guy with SP-5?
Wang...
Ling?
He's too weak!
Very well,
I'll remember you.
I need around SP-400 to be in the general class.
Croak,
croak.
I just need a little bit more to destroy the seal.
Wait!
This BGM!
Could he be...?
Impossible!
How could it be
him?
Yah!
Urgh,
argh!
Surrender your Spiritual Force!
Ah!
Good,
a side dish has just served itself at my doorstep.
I hate to be disturbed when eating Crispy Noodles.
Wh...
Why?
There's no mistake.
That year,
I was defeated by this boy accompanied by his own BGM.
Hmm.
My spiritual force is now locked at its minimum.
Oh,
right.
I must pretend like I'm doing my best.
Yah!
No, no, I must find a way out!
If he lands the punch,
my soul will be completely destroyed!
Hey!
Eh?
The screen?
What happened?
What's with that white light?
Is it broken?
I don't know! What happened?
Huh?
Wow!
This is...?
You must be kidding!
Ah!
What's going on?
I didn't do anything yet.
*Ha-ha: An affectionate nickname for the Sky-Swallowing Toad.
*Ha-ha!
Ha-ha!
What's wrong?
Croak...
Ha-ha
Did that guy just kill Tuntian-ha?!
Hmph.
Haven't you noticed?
Sun Rong pretty much exhausted Tuntian-ha's health bar with her attack.
That guy with SP-5
simply dealt the final blow.
You're wrong.
Every registered hit,
would cause the protective membrane to light up.
Why didn't it light up this time?
I see.
So it faked its death.
The rest of its spiritual force escaped in soul form.
Wang Ling.
Yes.
I'm here.
You're
attending the gifted class.
Huh?
Gifted Class
Students of the gifted class!
I am Pan Shengcong,
your head instructor.
Heaven Rewards the Diligent
With Preparation Comes Success
This is our
first lesson in summoning.
Has anyone learned this before?
The space around us is filled with spiritual bodies.
What we need to do, is
open a tunnel in such a space.
Your spiritual force
will determine the size of your tunnel.
Most summoning techniques involve drawing Spiritual Seals or chanting Incantations.
First, draw a Spiritual Seal.
Next, inject your Spiritual Force into it.
A Spiritual Beast will then be summoned.
All in all,
the strength of the summoned soul
is proportional to your SP.
Whoa.
I'll first teach the most basic summoning skill of all.
Summoning Spells
Spiritual Seal
Summon
Incantation
Soul
SP
Alright.
The key points of basic summoning are as what I've just said.
Show me what you've got.
Yes, Ma'am!
O' souls near me,
heed my call!
Expel the darkness of the world
and show me the way!
Hey...
there's no need to be this intense when summoning...
Demon Lord, descend to earth!
I offer my blood and spirit!
Appear, Divine Dragon!
Fulfill my wish!
Interesting.
Let me try it!
Gyaa! Creep!
Wait, wait!
I can explain!
Wow!
Sun Rong, what did you summon?
Is that a Spiritual Beast?
Amazing!
She can already summon a Spiritual Beast?
It looks like the soul of a stray dog.
It's not a Spiritual Beast, right?
There's no way I could summon anything powerful.
Damn it!
How much SP do I need to summon a Spiritual Beast?
Everyone seems to have succeeded with their summons.
Wang Ling,
how about you?
Did you not understand what I demonstrated?
Do you need me to repeat it?
Forget it,
I'll just play it by ear.
Sigh...
with so many alien lifeforms in nearby dimensions,
even I am clueless about what I might summon.
Tun...Tuntian-ha?!
Why?
Why is it you again?!
Yeah.
Don't panic!
I'm here!
Urgh.
They've combined!
Wow, it's so cute!
It's adorable!
Let's take care of it together!
Sounds good!
*Er-ha: The 'ha' of Tuntian-ha, the Sky-Swallowing Toad,  (吞天蛤) is a homophone of the popular endearment of Husky, Er'ha (二哈).
Then, shall we call it *Er-ha?
How's that?
Yeah, yeah!
*Green: A color often used to describe someone who was cheated on.
*Why are you so green though?
That's because Tuntian-ha is green!
Uwaa, his fur feels so good!
Croak!!!
Episode 1
Wang Ling's Triple Kill of Tuntian-ha
du
独行穿梭于夜幕下的孤寂
du xing chuan suo yu ye mu xia de gu ji
du
xing
chuan
In solitude, I walk into the lonely night
xing
chuan
俯瞰这行色匆匆的步履
fu kan zhe xing se cong cong de bu lv
fu
kan
zhe
xing
se
cong
de
bu
lv
looking down at the hurried steps beneath.
fu
kan
zhe
xing
se
cong
de
bu
lv
万物已通明
wan wu yi tong ming
wan
wu
yi
tong
ming
As the world becomes lucid to me
wan
wu
yi
tong
ming
眼中的闪烁
yan zhong de shan shuo
yan
zhong
de
shan
shuo
the gleam in my eyes
zhong
de
shan
shuo
从不露痕迹
cong bu lu hen ji
cong
bu
lu
hen
ji
never leaves a single trace.
cong
bu
lu
hen
ji
The Daily Life of the Immortal King
真实的幻象 如何闪避
zhen shi de huan xiang  ru he shan bi
zhen
shi
de
huan
xiang
ru
he
shan
bi
How can I avoid these illusions so convincing?
zhen
shi
de
huan
xiang
ru
he
shan
bi
究竟做多少防御
jiu jing zuo duo shao fang yu
jiu
jing
zuo
duo
shao
fang
yu
How many layers of defense
jing
zuo
duo
shao
fang
yu
能抵挡寂寞入侵
neng di dang ji mo ru qin
neng
di
dang
ji
mo
ru
qin
do I need to keep this loneliness at bay?
neng
di
dang
又能对荣耀胜败
you neng dui rong yao sheng bai
you
neng
dui
rong
yao
sheng
bai
All the while pretending not to care
neng
dui
rong
yao
sheng
bai
jia
假装不在意
jia zhuang bu zai yi
jia
zhuang
bu
zai
yi
about failure and glory?
zhuang
bu
zai
yi
听自己的心
ting zi ji de xin
ting
zi
ji
de
xin
I listen to my heart—
要徘徊还是所向披靡
yao pai huai hai shi suo xiang pi mi
yao
pai
huai
hai
shi
suo
xiang
pi
mi
Is it lost or is it set on victory?
pai
huai
hai
shi
suo
xiang
pi
mi
So you can watch me now
So
you
can
watch
watch
me
now
打破时空的封印
da po shi kong de feng yin
da
po
shi
kong
de
feng
yin
Breaking the seal of space and time.
da
po
shi
kong
de
feng
yin
xuan
旋转着对抗着冲击着旧的一切
xuan zhuan zhe dui kang zhe chong ji zhe jiu de yi qie
xuan
zhuan
zhe
dui
kang
zhe
chong
Whirling, resisting and fighting all remnants of the past.
zhuan
zhe
dui
kang
zhe
chong
撕裂夜空的平静
si lie ye kong de ping jing
si
lie
ye
kong
de
ping
jing
Destroying the tranquility of the night sky.
si
lie
ye
kong
de
ping
jing
So you can watch me now
So
you
can
watch
watch
me
now
when I was set free.
When I was set free
When
I
was
set
free
When
I
was
set
free
You’re gonna be in fear
You’re
gonna
be
in
fear
You’re
gonna
be
in
fear
and get your defeat.
and get your defeat
and
get
your
defeat
and
get
your
defeat
wo
我欲无名
wo yu wu ming
wo
yu
wu
ming
I wish to be nameless
yu
wu
ming
任这昼夜颠倒
ren zhe zhou ye dian dao
ren
zhe
zhou
ye
dian
dao
no matter if day & night reverse.
ren
zhe
zhou
ye
dian
dao
wo
我欲藏身
wo yu cang shen
wo
yu
cang
shen
I wish for seclusion,
yu
cang
shen
奈何世间无序
nai he shi jian wu xu
nai
he
shi
jian
wu
xu
but chaos is all I see.
he
shi
jian
wu
xu
bu
不欲化仙
bu yu hua xian
bu
yu
hua
xian
I never sought immortality,
yu
hua
xian
却投身战斗里
que tou shen zhan dou li
que
tou
shen
zhan
dou
li
yet I'm devoted to fighting
que
tou
shen
zhan
dou
li
攻破 乘胜追击
gong po  cheng sheng zhui ji
gong
po
cheng
sheng
zhui
ji
breaking through and doubling down when I'm in the lead.
gong
po
cheng
sheng
zhui
ji