This is an overlay of softsubs on the official video.
Brought to you by Guodong Subs.
"Shelter" by Shuangsheng
Composed by / Yixihe
Lyrics by / Yuli
Supervised by / 薄荷映像
Visual / Nekoloco    Audio Mixing / Gordon Davidson (U.S.A.)
AE / Digifan    Master Tape / Li Jincheng
Music Production / 联合麦田    Producer / Yixihe
Translator / CloudAyun    Proofreader / K    QC / Wuzimiko    Timer, Effect & Encoder / Emily
Brought to you by Guodong Subs
In my soul, there is a young child
ostracized by the colorful world;
in my dreams, a piece of the sky
gentler than the fickle earth.
At the crossroads of naivete and maturity,
I'm too scared to choose.
Adults come in all shapes and sizes—
See you at the guild!
is there a right and wrong?
I wander alone,
fearing of being a burden.
But you said,
“Don't worry, come with me.”
I will carry your beliefs
as I grapple against time,
taking on all the highs and lows.
Sharing a common wish,
I will turn promises into wings
and fly towards tomorrow.
No matter the dangers,
no matter how far I am away from you right now,
I will always return to where our story began.
Fengxi!
Luozhu!
Tianhu!
And so I began to see: the trails of wind,
the meanings in flowers;
seasons took on names.
I've found my shelter,
Then from now on,
this will be your home.
a view that I must protect.
There is someone in my memory,
who is happiness to me;
there is a mark on my soul,
that is the proof of our bond.
Put me down!
Countless buildings unfurl beneath me,
shoes worn out from scaling thousands of peaks.
You are the place where I belong.
Your eyes burn with determination,
your hands grip starlight—
you break through the fiercest storms.
You give me a shoulder to lean on
and power boundless,
no longer preplexed by love.
No matter the dangers,
no matter how far I am away from you right now,
I will always come back and find you once more
on that horizon we first met.
At the crossroads of the past and the future,
please let me choose to
hold on tightly to your hand,
together we shall walk on.