Brought to you by Guodong Subs
I can warm your bed
Please take me home
Meow
Let's call him… Xiaohei.
Huh? That's it?
*bai: white
*hei: black
I'm Xiaobai. He's Xiaohei. Isn't that perfect?
Isn't that too casual? ...
Are you saying... you guys named me casually as well?
Now that I think about it...
The name Luo Xiaohei has quite some depth to it.
It's awake.
Hey
Huh?
You scared him.
Xiaohei~
Don't be afraid~
Come out.
Sorry
Mom! Where did the plate go?
I don't know. It wasn't me~
I know. Could Xiaohei have dragged it in?
No way... Go take a look?
Could there be something...
Oh?
He came out.
What happened?
Why is it suddenly so well-behaved...
You must've scared him just then.
His tongue is blue.
Should a cat's tongue be blue?
How would I know?
Alright.
Go buy cat litter and a litter box tomorrow.
Huh? What's that?
It's the kitty's toilet.
Can't it use the bathroom?
Find me a cat that can sit on the toilet.
Well...
Huh?
Meow~
You're definitely not an ordinary cat~
So where do you really come from?
You're so well-behaved~
Your owner must've liked you a lot, huh?
Yeah.
They must've had no choice
but to leave you.
From now on,
I'll be your owner.
My name is Luo Xiaobai.
Let's get along well~
Xiaohei~
Xiao-...
Xiaohei?
Actually...
I am a cursed prince.
Thank you for breaking the curse.
Is it because I kissed you?
Yes.
That's so cliche~
Tonight...
Would you like to go to my castle?
I want to express my gratitude~
I can't...
I have class tomorrow~
I'll pick you up this weekend~
Hahahaha... OK.
Diting, the Aurora Pearl has been stolen.
Do you acknowledge your fault?
I do.
I will find the Aurora Pearl and bring it back.
It won't be easy to find in this crowded world.
The demon took a blow from me. I beat it back into its original form.
It should be nearby.
Alright then. You must bring it back.
Yes.
This is a free fansub by fans for fans. We do not own the copyright. Please support the official channel.
Translator: Wang Huan
First proof: Black and Blue     Second proof: K     QC: Cupcake
Timer, Effect & Encoder: Yuuki
REMAKE