Brought to you by Guodong Subs
This is an overlay of softsubs on the official video. It can be toggles on and off.
All views shall go to Tencent's official youtube channel.
Translator: Sophia   First proof: Bronco   Second proof: Agogo
Effects & Encoder: Yuuki    QC: Wuzimiko
Energy
measures the kinetic conversion of matter.
It's abbreviated as
E.
In the world that I live in,
the succession, growth, and death of life forms
cannot exist without a mysterious form of energy
other than the pure matter conversion of flesh and blood.
This energy
is called Qi,
or
Innate Qi.
The existence of Qi
allowed us to transform from mindless flesh
into living beings with soul and consciousness.
Similarly,
due to the law of conservation of energy,
the Qi within our bodies
will be gradually consumed.
Thus,
we must face aging and death.
Only a few could
be aware of Qi, and learn to control this kind of energy in their bodies.
In the eyes of ordinary people,
these people
possess extraordinary abilities.
In their own circles,
they call themselves
the Outcast.
Yin-Yang is the root of Xuan.
All of Qi sprouts from the same.
Cultivate despite any calamity.
To demonstrate my abilities.
Under grandpa's tutelage, I became an Outcast as a child.
He asked me to hide this.
So I grew up an average Joe
for the twelve years after his death.
But, in the end,
I couldn't escape it.
After embroiling myself in the Outcast world,
I gradually realized
that everything
was related to
*The Chaos of Jia Shen: a fierce battle that happened among the outcasts in 1944, during the period of Anti-Japanese War (1937-1945).
*the Chaos of Jia Shen.
*Quan Xing: "to preserve nature", from The Huainan Zi (淮南子). Quan(全) means all, or preserve. Xing(性) means nature.
*Quan Xing,
an organization repelled by all Outcast powers.
However,
in 1944, some disciples from righteous sects
*WuGenSheng: the official leader of Quan Xing. His name meant "rootless and thrive".
swore brotherhood with *WuGenSheng, the leader of Quan Xing.
They're called
"the 36 Betrayers".
Various sects got together to hunt them down
in the name of housecleaning.
But their real aim was to
find and seize the secret of the arts, created by eight of the 36 Betrayers.
The eight of them
created unheard-of arts of incomparable ingenuity from thin air.
That's
"the Eight Incredible Arts".
Of the Eight Incredible Arts,
the arts that have been made known are
*Dispatch of Detained Spirit: *Dispatch of Detained Spirit: the art of being able to detain spirits and then dispatch them to do things as they want. Ju(拘) means detain. Ling(灵) means spirits or souls. Qian(遣) means dispatch. Jiang(将) means general or military. It's the extreme of abilities of the Shaman and Witches.
Feng Tianyang's *Dispatch of Detained Spirit,
*Tongtian Talisman: one of the Eight Incredible Arts which can create a talisman unbound by limits. Tong(通) means reach or communication. Tian(天) refers to the heavens, where immortals, spirit or gods live. Lu(箓) means talisman.
Zheng Zibu's *Tongtian Talisman,
*Fenghou QiMen: Qimen (奇门) is the art summed up by Fenghou(风后). It was said that Fenghou had simplified the original version from 4320 situations to 1080 situations.
*Fenghou QiMen,
and
*The Origin of Qi: one of the Eight Incredible Arts. Qi(炁) is a special type of energy. Ti(体) means physical form. Yuan(源) means the origin. Liu(流) refers to a style of cultivation art.
my grandpa's *The Origin of Qi.
That's why I had to live in hiding
with my grandpa since I was born.
Once a normal college student,
*Nadoutong Express Company: an outcast organization controlled by Chinese government to restrain the outcasts, maintain the stability and balance of the outcast world. Na(哪) means wherever. Dou(都) means all. Tong(通) means work or to go to.
I'm now forced to join the *Nadoutong Express Company
as an ordinary employee.
Water coats the argent bridge with sparkles. Sun strips the aureate stage of its shade.
Hear the pigeon's whistle fly towards Beijing's opening gate.
Sage, taoist or freaks set things up in flames
are all welcome to my bait-and-switch game.
When the winds and clouds collide, abrupt thunder shall crack through the sky.
As Yin and Yang reverse, the sparrow once caged
is now hovering on the sly.
Drum and Bell knock the world awake in this new era's game of ill intent.
May you be always careful till the end.
Left to my doorstep. North to this alley's end.
Take the 2nd Ring, just ahead. See you on the overpass, my friend.
Here, we hide all blades behind our backs.
Fat rats and mayflies, creep up on through the crack.
You'll always be a step late in this Mahjong game.
Cause I took the banker's title, and I'd never be arrogant.
Qi is overflowing here, where all streams run into.
In my chest, lies a line between good and evil.
Only when polished in this world can one outstand from the mortal world.
My gratitude for you is beyond words.
From the West, comes my witty gal
who shows no mercy as she smacks.
In the South, stands a squinting pal
who is so competitive, yet a real stand-up friend.
The Shameless from the north bears talent that'd put others to shame
who grew up as an orphan, yet back his friends up, even risking his name.
Blocked all ends, trapped you in the dead end.
I leap like a carp, leaving no trace behind.
Such a chaotic world of mortals though!
May you be safe wherever you go.
Episode 1
Total Amount
Inventory Checked
Amount to Record into Inventory: 5
Recorded Category: 8
Did you summon me
just to sort some boxes?
Keep your head down.
Focus on the work.
Good.
This one is great too.
Why are you taking photos?
Whatcha talking about?
Look,
I'm praising Chulan.
Came to work once he's off Mount Longhu.
A company man at heart!
Alright,
why did you ask Chulan to come in early today?
For what?
Bro Si.
You didn't ask me over today just to sort boxes, right?
Is it about what I said last night?
Well,
I didn't make it clear yesterday.
In fact, it's ok to tell you everything.
We all know the truth of the Chaos of Jia Shen.
It's just an excuse for the various sects
to hunt the 36 Betrayers, so that they could seize the Eight Incredible Arts for themselves.
Thank you.
Actually,
my grandpa had two choices at that time.
Either to be on the run,
or to return to Mount Longhu.
Running
meant that he would be hunted as long as he still lives.
If he returned,
he might face a punishment even harsher.
But, there might have been another possibility...
*Enlightenment of Taoist Master: TianShi(天师) means Taoist Master. Du(度) means enlighten. All the Taoist Masters will enlighten their successor, who will be the next Taoist Master.
He could have received the Enlightenment of Taoist Master* as the successor.
However, I'm guessing the one who loses the Enlightenment
may die.
So, if my grandpa had
went back and accepted the Enlightenment,
not only would he kill his Shifu,
*Shixiong: the senior disciple of the same generation. Shi(师) means to learn from. Di(兄) means elder brother.
but he would also deprive his *shixiong, Zhang Zhiwei, of his rightful place as the next Taoist Master.
So, he
chose to run for a lifetime.
As for the way to create the Eight Incredible Arts?
The Taoist Masters of Mount Longhu knew the answer all along.
The answer lies within
the Enlightenment of Taoist Master.
That's why my dad couldn't find any clues.
The seal of this Enlightenment must have existed for ages,
it might even date back to the first Taoist Master, Zhang Ling.
Yes.
So, no matter if it's for Old Taoist Master,
or to find the truth for Sis Bao-er,
I cannot accept the Enlightenment.
The secret of a seal that lasted for over 2000 years...
It's ok, Bro San.
Our only aim is to find out Sis Bao-er's origin.
It wouldn't concern matters from over 2000 years ago.
Yeah.
First, we could figure out who the 36 Betrayers are.
How, though?
Thanks to the World Sacrificial Rites,
we met many witnesses of that incident back then.
*Shiye: Shifu's Shifu. Shi(师) means to learn from. Ye(爷) means grandfather, and is often used to address somebody respectfully.
After tricking *Shiye this time,
we probably won't get anything else from him.
Both Elder Lv and Elder Wang
wouldn't give us any answers.
Therefore,
Elder Lu Jin
is our only choice for now.
I'll find a chance to ask him.
Glad to hear you say that.
But, I know a man related to the Eight Incredible Arts too.
Right, Chulan,
put Elder Lu Jin aside for now.
He has a lot to deal with after the Rites.
I happen to have a mission here.
The client named you.
Three
days
ago
Bro Du,
since there's no traffic,
could you speed up?
Any faster and I'll receive demerit points.
Relax, President Ye.
We'll arrive home soon.
*Xiao Ye-zi: an endearment that elders could use to call the youth. Xiao(小) means young or little. Ye(也) represents the name of Wang Ye. Zi(子) is used to address the person.
*Xiao Ye-zi!!!
You're finally back!
Mom.
Why didn't you visit me more instead of wasting away on that mountain?
I missed you to death!
Here, let me have a good look at you.
Mom,
my dad...
Ah, you got thinner again.
Look at your face.
You have dark circles.
What's going on with my dad?
Is the food there not good?
Wait for me.
I'll make you noodles with soy bean!
Just wait.
*Xiao Ye: an endearment the elders could use to call the youth. Xiao(小) means young or little. Ye(也) represents the name of Wang Ye.
*Xiao Ye!
Bro Yi. Sister-in-law.
Third uncle!
You've grown taller!
Bro Yi,
how's dad?
I heard from Bro Du that dad's health...
Your dad, he...
Xiao... Ye...
Dad.
Xiao Ye...
You're finally back?
We've found him the best doctor.
They said that it's asthenia of stomach and spleen, due to over-anxiety.
Your dad also has severe psychasthenia and insomnia.
Xiao Ye...
It's okay.
Don't worry.
It's all because I miss you too much.
*Wudang (Sect): named after the Wudang Mountains. Wu(武) means Zhenwu. Dang(当) means deserve. The founder named the sect as "Wudang(武当)", because he hoped that his disciples will be responsible, courageous enough to fight, and still bear kindness in heart.
The old leader of Wudang called me two days ago,
telling me that you're no longer a part of Wudang
and you will be back home soon.
After hearing that,
I got so much better.
How great this is!
Come and help dad with our family business.
Xiao Ye.
Asthenia of stomach and spleen.
Psychasthenia.
Depression. Insomnia.
I can't find any related medicines at all.
*Liuwei Dihuang: pill for the deficiency of kidney, dizziness, tinnitus and so on.
*Liuwei Dihuang.
*Goji berry: is good for liver, kidney and lung.
*Goji berry.
*Dried sea horses: is good for kidney.
*Dried sea horses.
Kangaroo Essence.
Damn.
These little blue pills...
Dad,
you'd better fake kidney deficiency next time.
Look at you!
Asthenia of stomach and spleen, insomnia
won't come for you.
I only did all this to keep you at home!
Mom,
see, he's all good now.
Wudang kicked you out anyway!
You'll have to behave yourself and help me!
Why put it that way?
Not being with Wudang is far from "resuming to the secular life"
I just came back for a short visit.
I'm relieved that you're fine.
I'll be on my way later.
Are you trying to drive me to my grave?!
Try me and I won't leave you a single cent!
I never asked for even for a single cent.
What did you say?
Xiao Ye-zi!
I'm so pissed!
You... we're family. That's unnecessary.
Stop fighting! Stop, you two!
Okay. Okay.
Alright, enough.
Calm down.
You!
Stop sulking.
My bad, I shouldn't have argued with you...
Geez, what for?
Xiao Ye is back, so what?
Really?
You hate him that much?
I don't hate him.
But his return makes me a bit depressed.
Why are you depressed over this?
Wang Yi, remember!
I am your wife,
and Taotao is your very own son.
Right now, aside from your parents,
we are your closest family,
also the ones who cares for you the most!
Xiao Ye is my own little brother!
But, if he returns to join the Corp,
he'll have an additional status
which may drive you down your position as the successor!
He's my family.
He's entitled to part of the Corp!
The position of the successor...belongs to whoever's more capable.
This family is still so dramatic.
You managed to defeat someone from the Zhuge family?
Incredible!
I didn't know that you're capable of that!
Looks like I don't stand a chance against you now.
Wudang then struck your name off right after.
What trouble did you cause?
It's complicated.
Bro Du, let's talk business.
How was it?
If not for your warning a few days ago,
I wouldn't notice that
the entire house has been searched.
I found bugs in many places.
Anything they moved,
they've put them back carefully.
Ordinary men wouldn't notice a thing.
A regular thief could never
do this secretly while avoiding
our security cameras.
Must've been Outcasts.
That's why...
who did you mess with?
Don't ask anything,
especially the details.
Would you still want to help me then?
Of course!
Hire some Outcasts to protect my family in secret,
but don't let them notice.
OK.
Money.
What money?
Of course, my family's paying for that.
Bro Du.
How could I have the money?
Hey!
I'm just your dad's assistant.
How could I use your family's money?
Do you know how expensive it is to hire Outcasts?
I can afford it, if we're hiring normal people.
Shall we hire some first?
No way.
Normal men are no match for them.
We must hire Outcasts.
Didn't expect myself to worry about money one day!
Bro Du,
contact Jin Yuanyuan and the others, will you?
*Mount Wudang: Wu(武) means Zhenwu. Dang(当) means deserve. Shan(山) means Mountains. Zhenwu also called Xuanwu(玄武Black Tortoise), is a Taoism God of North reigning over water and killings. The name is derived from the praise: only Zhenwu deserves the fame of its name(非真武不足当之)
You've been a Taoist on *Mount Wudang for so many years.
Finally you remember your childhood friends!
Contacting us as soon as you're back...
what are you up to?
I...
Beer! Wine!
Pour him some alcohol and dump his tea!
God,
do you hate me or something?!
Why did you drink so much?
I just wanted Jin to set something up for me and make some money.
I can't believe that for money, I would...
Even though you're outside,
your house
is still being watched.
We've got ourselves a tail as well.
They are nearby.
Get in the car.
They didn't do anything,
just tailing us.
Annoying!
Looks like they'll keep on going...
Plan for a protracted war?
What a pain.
We can't shake them off.
Stay close.
Looks like they haven't noticed us yet.
So annoying!
Stay close!
Where are we?
White Cave Overpass.
Drive up there!
So wise of you!
Where are they?
Left! Left!
Down below!
Turn right?
Use the navigation!
I'm using it!
I am following its lead!
We are trapped!
This must be a formation!
What kind of scocery is this?
It's horrible!
Why can't we get off?!
If you could leave the overpass within two days, kudos to you!
What's that noise?
I don't know.
Bro Du!
Who the hell are they?
Into the world for a walk.
The bluish lotus stands tall and shall never back down.
The clanging jade beads of the abacus—
Here's a calculated plan for the whole shebang!
Greeting with a courtesy smile without a flaw.
Hear the quips and gags roll off this tongue.
Rake his past up. Size his skill up.
Venturing to this fair land.
Seek young talents to subdue evil with fangs.
Helping the wild goose back to its flock.
Once the heart find its way, the monkey shall roam free with its gang!
Let the wisdom of ploy talk.
Stir up the water and turn this world upside-down.
What a messy past!
They laugh at him for being clueless.
What do you deem as just? Depends on where your heart is.
Professing himself to be vulgar and aim for nothing.
Just let tattle and prate be gone with the wind.
They sneer at him for being stupid and timid.
Tide over suffering for her limpid eyes under his heart.
If there ain't a favorable wind, he might as well gather a storm.
With faith by his side, he rides after his true nature.