[ADVERTISEMENT]
This is an overlay of softsubs on a third party channel.
Please also support the official channel.
Brought to you by Guodong Subs
Translator: Sophia & Shiken      Proofreader: Wuzimiko       QC: Roqubot
Lyrics Translator: Sophia, Shiken & Wuzimiko      Timer, Effect & Encoder: Wuzimiko & KFC
Liao Zhong from South Region...
is dead.
The murder suspect is
a temp-worker under him,
Chen Duo.
The head office has issued an order.
They're gathering the other 6 temps for the first time
to join hands and arrest the defector.
They demand to see her,
dead or alive.
If we turn down the mission,
they'll have an excuse to investigate North Region's temp.
Worst case scenario:
they'll retract Bao-er's status as a temp-worker.
If we accept the mission,
the other temp-workers may uncover Bao-er's secret.
That's why,
Zhang Chulan,
I'd like to hear your thoughts.
Qi, whenever
tainted by a hint of blood,
fiddles around with real, vibrant lives.
Trying to fill an insanely restless heart;
that's all the meaning there is to it.
Unwilling
to be seared
with any mark.
Trying to sever the traces that may become binding someday.
Drifting to the East. And West. Persistent. Carefree.
Just unwilling to be engulfed. Reckless. Break free.
Walking freely with nothing under my feet.
Detached.
Shunned.
Arrogant.
Humble.
Wild.
Eyes fixed only forward.
This is what it looks like to be alive.
Goodwill.
Reason.
Honor.
Human world. Righteousness. The pale truth.
How many delusions have they extinguished?
*Zhengyue (正月): First month of the lunisolar calendar.
There are no flowers to pick during Zhengyue.
Yet when frost rains down on the plum blossoms, they bloom by themselves.
The Outcast S4
Episode 1
Thank you for your patience.
This flight has taken off.
The flight distance is 2276 km.
The flight time is around 3 hours.
Dear passenger,
the in-flight meals are in preparation.
Please wait patiently.
This is the phone designated for this mission.
Super strong signal.
Use this card to cover your mission expenses.
The other 6 temps have all joined the Wechat group.
You may communicate in chat.
Northeast
North
Central
Southwest
East
Group Name: Make you bend over (Just kidding)
Northeast
North
Central
East
No one's saying anything.
Say "Hello"?
Nice to meet you all.
This is our first time collaborating.
I'll be in your care.
07:38 P.M.
No one's online -_-
Hello
Hello, North.
I'm a guy.
Hello, North!
I'm a guy. 39 years old. A little violent. My hobby is... killing...
39 years old.
Nice to meet you...
Wechat Red Packet
Panshan Road   10007m
Nice to meet you...
Loading
East Region
Too slow. Better luck next time!
These guys...
- Too slow. Better luck next time! -
Opened 5 red packet(s) (182.82 yuan in total)
Southeast        35.40 yuan
Northwest       15.90 yuan
Northeast        57.20 yuan
East                       2.22 yuan
.                            72.10 yuan
So everyone's here.
Nice to meet you all.
Looks like we're not the only ones worried about exposing our identity.
Forget it.
You two should get ready to leave.
From the intel,
they've identified where Chen Duo was last seen.
Here are your plane tickets.
Isn't this too rushed?
At least, till I get back to school tomorrow...
Tomorrow?
Might as wait till the plane leaves.
Excuse me,
two rooms please.
One room.
Easier to talk.
Easier to act too.
11:30 P.M.
Have you all arrived?
As expected,
zero response.
No one said anything at all.
What's with this awkward atmosphere in the chat?
Everyone's arrived, right?
Did no one mention anything about meeting up?
Looks like no one is interested.
Thought so.
If not for this mission,
I wouldn't want to meet you guys too.
You've all read
the mission brief, right?
After Chen Duo reached here,
she got in touch with someone called Wan Liangcai.
Wan Liangcai
runs a snack restaurant.
No Outcast-related background.
Chen Duo subsequently disappeared.
Since no one intends to show their faces,
I'll make contact with Wan Liangcai.
I'm fine with completing the mission on my own.
Bro Xiao, I'll go with you.
Hi, everyone.
I'm from the Southwest.
You can call me Qiu-er.
It's rare for 6 temps to act together.
This mission is so exciting!
I'm just curious how strong that Chen Duo is.
Don't take it too easy, stupid Qiu-er.
All intel about Chen Duo was provided by my informer.
I should've been the first one here.
However, when I went to meet him,
he'd already been killed.
The wound is different from what's recorded of Chen Duo's skills.
Chen Duo
probably has a partner.
Hi,
Bro Xiao.
Southwest,
Wang Zhenqiu.
So?
Let's meet them?
I've asked.
That Mr. Wan should be clean.
Chen Duo came here
to ask about a granny called
Mei Jinfeng.
He did serve a granny whose surname is Mei.
She couldn't stop praising the lamb noodles he cooked.
She told him she doesn't like to go out
and asked him to send the noodles to where she lives in seclusion.
Chen Duo got the address of that granny.
Just now, I got my hands on a copy too.
Also,
there is a letter
left by Chen Duo.
Don't open it!!!
Qiu.
Keep some distance.
As I expected,
they're only targeting Xiao.
*Gu: venomous insect / poison made from poisonous insects, worms or beetles.
*Gu sure are interesting.
Bro Xiao.
If I saw that correctly,
*Infinitely Compassionate Hand: it is one of the 72 unique skills of Shaolin.
was that the *Infinitely Compassionate Hand?
Qiu,
a word of advice.
Don't act all chummy with me.
Besides,
when I ask you to stay away from me,
you must be obedient.
Don't open it!!!
Bro Xiao, haven't you dealt with
Gu practitioners before?
Don't touch anything related to the Holy Child of Gu...
Have these sneaky guys been
watching us the whole time?
Hell.
Ok.
Thank you, Bro Si.
Don't touch anything related to the Holy Child of Gu...
11:56 P.M.
Everyone!
I asked a North Region colleague
to investigate this just now.
*Quan Xing: "to preserve nature", from The Huainan Zi (淮南子). Quan(全) means all, or preserve. Xing(性) means nature.
This Mei Jinfeng
is from *Quan Xing
I asked a North Region colleague
to investigate this just now.
This Mei Jinfeng
is from Quan Xing
and...
This Mei Jinfeng
is from Quan Xing
and...
she joined Quan Xing in 1940
a super heavyweight
Get lost!
Shameless.
Don't ever come to me again!
Oh, Jinfeng-er.
Hear me out.
It's just that I haven't seen you in so long,
so I was a bit...
No! No! I won't listen!
All right.
If you don't wish to listen, so be it.
Bro Xia.
I know.
Your...
feelings for me.
But you should know!
My heart
belongs only to that man.
Jin Feng-er.
It's been so many years.
Actually,
you're no longer
that important to me.
Xia Liuqing!
You as*hole!
Why are you mad?
You only care about the Sect Leader anyways.
Do you know how many years I spent staying a virgin for you?
Fine, fine, fine.
Forget it.
That thing I need.
Tell me,
where did you put it?
Why would I tell you, old man?
Don't be like that.
Good evening,
Granny Jinfeng.
Would you mind
coming with me?
How many years has it been?
To think a stranger would visit an old hag like me.
Please leave the mountain with me.
I'm getting on in years.
I don't want to go anywhere.
I insist.
Let it rest, Jin Feng-er.
In times like these,
you should rely on men.
Not bad.
You form is steady, and you breathe light.
A talent indeed.
Grandpa.
I...
Doesn't matter.
I don't care who you are or where you're from.
Anyone who troubles Jin Feng
will ultimately become a corpse!
This is...
a living Gu.
King Snake.
As a Gu practitioner,
I can't believe you'd walk straight towards the enemy.
Young'uns nowadays
are so insensible.
That's not it.
Grandpa,
I'm not here to make enemies of you nor Granny Jinfeng.
Also,
I'm not a Gu practitioner.
I am a Gu.
This Mei Jinfeng
is from Quan Xing
and...
she joined Quan Xing in 1940
a super heavyweight
beware of ambush
Not bad, North.
You detected them from that far back.
Good.
There's no need to kill
opponents of this level.
Golden Bell Cover.
Flower-pinching Finger.
Sharp moves, Bro Xiao.
Who are you guys?
Forget it.
This one
is threatening enough.
Clear to kill.
Bro Xiao,
I'm sure you can handle her.
But that'll take so much effort.
Looks like this mission
isn't as simple as we thought.
Allow me
to handle this.
What difference does it make?
Lucky ♡
YOU PERV!
Bro Xiao,
the reason you can't hurt her
isn't because she's powerful or anything.
She's just wearing a shield armour.
It's tier is so low
that I can't call it a treasure.
An artifact at most.
It only responds to malice.
Whether you refined it yourself or got it as a gift,
save yourself the embarrassment
of bringing something of this caliber next time.
Pervert,
don't be so smug!
What did you do?!
Why did my armor...?!
Because I bear no malice,
and didn't attack you.
You'll feel no pain,
only pleasure.
Don't come over!
See?
Violence isn't the only way
to render someone helpless.
I once pestered an uncle
to teach me his modified Extendable Arm.
That fist technique isn't bad,
but I didn't like how violent it was,
so I modified it.
This is what I created.
Love
Massage.
What's wrong, Sis Bao-er?
It's really similar to one of the 18 moves.
Are we gonna just watch from the sidelines?
And do nothing?
It'd be great if that's really the case.
These temp-workers
really surprised me.
Zhenqiu,
stop now.
She's too pitiful
for you to continue.
Who are you?
I...
I'm from the Northwest.
You may call me Meng.
Meng.
Pitiful?
Look over there.
If I let Xiao shatter her shield with brute force,
it'd be a lot worse for her.
Bro Xiao,
would you blame me for taking your prey?
The mission made it clear that
the only one I can kill
is Chen Duo.
Gentlemen.
Actually,
the reason I'm here
is to try and negotiate.
Is it possible that
you let Chen Duo live?
Biyou Village will always open its doors for you.
Welcome
I stand by the village entrance to give you a warm welcome.
The people of Biyou are always trustworthy.
Sentiments. Happiness.
Thank you for coming all the way.
Biyou Village never disappoints its guests.
We are the same. How could we be xenophobic?
Every corner of Biyou Village is filled with love and care.
How friendly! How lively!
Delighting you always!
Come~ Come~
Come look around the village!
Just come with me...
Look at the mountains and waters, untouched by man!
The mountain ♪ka-ka-beng-ha-ha-di♪ How passionate and lively!
Our Village Head's surname is Ma and everyone praises him.
Just like the bright moon... moonlight, pure and flawless.
Biyou Village welcomes you.
I brought flowers just to celebrate your arrival.
Biyou Village will always welcome you with open arms.
Passionate, and always delightful.
Welcome