Brought to you by Guodong Subs
This is an overlay of softsubs on a third party channel.
Please also support the official channel.
Translator: Cheska & LY    Proofreader: Wuzimiko   QC: Roqubot
Lyrics Translator: LY, Natsu, Roqubot & Wuzimiko    Timer, Effect & Encoder: Yuuki
On the path to immortality
before a library of herbs and pills
there's far too much to take in
Just who is singing
who is hesitating
and who is standing atop the clouds?
Out of the many who have come
how many achieved the Way,
rushing to a finish?
Just who becomes anxious,
and who is carefree?
On the outside
I pretend to be weak
You don't understand,
hence you're confused
Just when, he asked,
will I achieve completion?
Could loneliness be
the secret to immortality?
Are mortals only allowed an ordinary life?
I want to cultivate as an Immortal
to remain young forever
My cultivation comes from hard work
and not from luck
I didn't come here
to sightsee
When I give it my all
it'll surpass your imagination
Even if the moon sleeps,
I will endure until sunrise
Why do I give my all?
It's all to become eternal
To prove that
even as an ordinary mortal
even when afraid,
shedding tears of fear
I can
break through
to the clear sky beyond the clouds
Reshaping my mortal body
through countless rebirths
until my primordial spirit
manifests like a blaze
and finally
harmonizing heaven and earth to become eternal
A Will Eternal
Episode 15
We're reaching Spirit Stream's grounds.
Junior brother Bai.
Hang in there.
You must hang in there!
Am... I going to die?
Xiaochun.
Mom!
My son.
You...
...must live!
You... must... live...
Mom!
This...
Impossible!
It's as if his spiritual Qi is trying to devour all life force.
Interesting.
Even if you got lucky just now
and broke into the 6th Level of Qi Condensation,
you're still nothing but an ant to me.
I can squash you anytime.
Throat Crushing Grasp!
Cheap tricks!
Senior brother Hou!
I...
...won't make it.
Senior brother Hou.
Beyond that mountain
lies the boundary stone.
Deliver the message to the Sect.
Promise me
that you will...
Senior brother Hou.
You must...
you must escape.
Promise me.
I promise.
What incredible regenerative powers!
If he was at the 8th Level of Qi condesation,
he would be a remarkable opponent.
I musn't collapse.
I have to save them.
Save...
them!
Violet Qi...
...Cauldron Summoning!
You are indeed a worthy opponent.
But this is
where you must die.
You should consider it an honor
to have forced me into using this spell.
After all, all who have seen it
are no longer in this world.
Is this
the power of the 9th Level of Qi Condensation?
This is the end!
That's not for you to decide!
What is that?
It's your tortoise master!
After you die, whatever secrets
you're hiding
will all be mine!
Well,
your two companions are up next.
I'll send them your way
to reunite in the underworld.
Dream on!
Spirit Stream Sect
Boundary Stone
You really are a mad dog.
You're a fool to think this would slow me down.
Bai Xiaochun.
A little more.
A little more!
You must hold it together!
Even my bones
are stronger than your fists!
9th Level of Qi Condensation?
You're still trash!
If you're unconvinced,
seek revenge after you're dead!
Your killer...
is Chen Heng!
Disciple Du Lingfei
has an urgent report to make!
I'm dragging you into my grave even if I die!
I...
...did it.
The Luochens have betrayed us.
Senior brother Feng died in battle.
Senior brother Hou is gravely injured.
Junior brother Bai
lured Young Master Luochen away alone,
his fate uncertain.
What tolls the Great Spirit Stream Bell?
Something grave must've happened.
What did you say?
Elder of the Enforcement Hall
Ouyang Jie
Betrayal?!
Repeat it!
According to Du Lingfei,
the Luochens have betrayed us.
Fragrant Cloud Peak disciple,
Bai Xiaochun, alone is holding off Chen Heng
and the other traitors,
his fate uncertain.
All Inner Sect Disciples in the three peaks along the south bank, heed my order!
Cancel all missions at once!
Halt all secluded practice!
Terminate all activities!
Gather at Mount Daoseed
at once!
The Luochen Clan
disregarded the protection and goodwill offered by Spirit Stream Sect
Spirit Stream Sect
Teleportation Formation
and blatantly colluded with the Blood Stream Sect to betray us.
The demonic viles of Luochen
have massacred the innocents and killed disciples of our sect
to achieve their goals.
Even now,
Bai Xiaochun from Fragrant Cloud Peak
is alone fighting a bloodied battle to save his sect mates.
His fate is uncertain.
All disciples, heed my order!
Mobilize immediately
to annihilate the traitors
and save your sect mates!
Annihilate the traitors!
Save our sect mates!
Young mistress.
We were too late.
Swirling petals dance in streams of
moonlight
The long road onward enveloped by icy mist
Is it but an illusion that setting stars lock eyes?
Life goes on as bygone dreams fade
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Pursuing my dreams alone
In wine I abandon the coming days
when reminiscing of past friends
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Smiling sheepishly as I watched the years wither away
to reveal a graying man young at heart
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Walking alone in the darkness
Only gratitude and kindness shall rest in my heart
Reflecting on a lifetime of recklessness
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Briefly, silly smiles mask the loneliness within
To where did the naive teen once dream of going?