Brought to you by Guodong Subs
This is an overlay of softsubs on a third-party video.
Please also support the official channel.
Translator: Cheska & LY    Proofreader: Wuzimiko    QC: Roqubot
Lyrics Translator: LY, Natsu, Roqubot & Wuzimiko    Timer, Effect & Encoder: Yuuki
On the path to immortality
before a library of herbs and pills
there's far too much to take in
Just who is singing
who is hesitating
and who is standing atop the clouds?
Out of the many who have come
how many achieved the Way,
rushing to a finish?
Just who becomes anxious,
and who is carefree?
On the outside
I pretend to be weak
You don't understand,
hence you're confused
Just when, he asked,
will I achieve completion?
Could loneliness be
the secret to immortality?
Are mortals only allowed an ordinary life?
I want to cultivate as an Immortal
to remain young forever
My cultivation comes from hard work
and not from luck
I didn't come here
to sightsee
When I give it my all
it'll surpass your imagination
Even if the moon sleeps,
I will endure until sunrise
Why do I give my all?
It's all to become eternal
To prove that
even as an ordinary mortal
even when afraid,
shedding tears of fear
I can
break through
to the clear sky beyond the clouds
Reshaping my mortal body
through countless rebirths
until my primordial spirit
manifests like a blaze
and finally
harmonizing heaven and earth to become eternal
A Will Eternal
Episode 13
I must stay alive.
I mustn't die.
I musn't die.
I mustn't die!
Run...
R-Run...!
Big bro Xiaochun.
I'm counting on you to bring my brother back.
No matter what,
you must relay the news back to the sect.
I'm counting on you.
A spell of mutual destruction.
Let's see if you have
[Member of the Luochen Clan]
[7th Level of Qi Condensation / 6th Level of Qi Condensation]
any spiritual weapons left to use.
Junior sister...
You, the Spirit Stream Sect, have always been self-righteous.
How do you feel now?
Look at that pretty little face.
Killing her seems like a waste-
Crazy bitch!
She's got a backbone, I must say.
Spare her the torment.
Kill her.
Even if I, Du Lingfei,
were to die,
I'll see that your entire clan gets annihilated!
Die!
Stop!
What are you waiting for?
Bai Xiaochun...!
Why did you come back?
Run already!
I can't...
leave you guys behind.
We'll get through this together.
From now on,
I swear to...
protect you guys!
I can't believe the coward who took off first
is back.
Then,
I'll kill you first!
He's so afraid of death!
How did he muster the courage to turn back?
Why?
Throat Crushing Grasp!
Don't tell me
this is the real Bai Xiaochun?
Seems like I underestimated you,
giving you an opening to exploit.
But this is the end.
My killer ghouls didn't kill him?
That's impossible.
Impossible!
This is...
the Undying Technique.
This can't be!
He's merely at the 5th Level of Qi Condensation.
*somato-spiritual cultivation (法体同修): a person who pursues both physical and spiritual cultivation.
So what if you practice *somato-spiritual cultivation?
To compensate for his lower cultivation,
he's taking a wound to close in for a kill!
This punch
is payback for hurting my seniors!
For the sake of us Luochens,
for the sake of our great plans,
you must...
die here!
This is...
Bai Xiaochun!
He's trading his life for yours!
Run!
Leave us!
Come on.
Bring it!
Violet Qi Cauldron Summoning!
His cultivation
far surpasses mine!
Violet Qi Cauldron Summoning!
Xiaochun!
Patriarch!
Chen Yue, he...!
He's dead?
Chen Yue's dead?
It was just three outer sect disciples.
He's at the 8th Level of Qi Condensation!
Could the Spirit Stream Sect
have known our plan,
and sent a cultivator in Foundation Establishment?   - What should we do?
The entire clan will be wiped out!
It's...
It's the Young Master.
Young Master!
He's here.
Heng'er.
[Chen Heng, Young Master of the Luochen Clan]
Leave this... to me.
I-
I'm still alive.
You're finally awake.
Senior sister.
Xiaochun!
We promised to go back together.
I can't go back on my words.
Keep still.
You were stabbed.
Stabbed?
Something like that—
you ought to say it first!
Don't worry.
I'll pull the sword out and seal your acupuncture point to stop the bleeding.
It'll hurt.
Bear with it.
Okay.
One,
two...
IT HURTS!
IT'S TOO PAINFUL!
I haven't started.
I...
I-I-I was too nervous.
D-
Did it just sp-
-spray blood?
Oh my god!
IT HURTS!!!
Hey!
If you keep moving
and tear the wound, that's on you!
Where's the courage you had when you came back to save us?
I'm talking to you!
I'm so tired.
Let me rest for a while...
The wound...
reopened...!
It's been half a year.
Your progress is impressive, Junior brother Bai.
I reckon that even our sect's Chosens
might be no match for you.
Practicing the Undying Technique
is a torture most cannot endure.
Looks like
I have to reevaluate him.
You flatter me, senior brother.
How could I measure up to the Chosens?
I used Violet Qi Cauldron Summoning on the spur of a moment.
It just came to me suddenly.
Junior brother, you're only at the 5th Level of Qi Condensation.
Yet the cauldron you summon
already wields such power.
It's truly impressive.
Don't you think our surroundings
have suddenly become quiet?
Get away!
Junior brother Bai!
Are you alright? Junior brother Bai!
Hurry up and go!
[Member of the Luochen Clan, 7th Level of Qi Condensation]
They should be nearby.
He was even forced to use the clan's forbidden spell.
Practitioner of somato-spiritual cultivation, and an extraordinary fighter.
From Spirit Stream's Outer Sect,
only a Chosen could defeat Chen Yue and his men
in a single blow.
I, Chen Heng, can finally drink
the blood of a Spirit Stream Sect's Chosen!
Hang in there!
With our current speed,
we can escape this mountain in three days!
Senior brother!
Junior brother Bai.
You've thrown away your safety for us.
I'm afraid...
I can only repay you in my next life.
Senior,
enough.
We will make it out alive!
Hurry!
There's still medicine.
Senior brother,
take the pill.
This must be the last pill we have.
Better not waste it.
You and I both understand
our current situation.
Those Luochens hot on our heels...
we're already lucky to have survived till this point.
Our enemies far surpass us in cultivation.
From now on,
It'll only get more dangerous.
Junior brother Bai may practice somato-spiritual cultivation,
but he's only at the 5th level of Qi Condensation.
I'm afraid
we can't hold them off for long.
This is now
our only option.
At least we have...
a chance this way.
I've sealed the entrace.
Rest up, and we'll leave
after recovering some strength.
I can feel the bloodlust in the valley thickening.
We've got company.
Could it be that
Patriarch Luochen's here?
Unlikely.
The Luochen Patriarch must sit in the the eye of the Great Spell of Spirit Reversal.
He wouldn't leave the spell now
that he's about to succeed.
But I heard
the Luochens have a Young Master
at the peak of the 9th Level of Qi Condensation.
9th Level?!
Young Master was right indeed.
With your injuries,
you would find a cave to hide and recuperate.
Young Master,
I found th-
Are you guys alright?
We're fine.
Swirling petals dance in streams of
moonlight
The long road onward enveloped by icy mist
Is it but an illusion that setting stars lock eyes?
Life goes on as bygone dreams fade
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Pursuing my dreams alone
In wine I abandon the coming days
when reminiscing of past friends
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Smiling sheepishly as I watched the years wither away
to reveal a graying man young at heart
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Walking alone in the darkness
Only gratitude and kindness shall rest in my heart
Reflecting on a lifetime of recklessness
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Briefly, silly smiles mask the loneliness within
To where did the naive teen once dream of going?