Brought to you by Guodong Subs
This is an overlay of softsubs on a third party channel.
Please also support the official channel.
Translator: Cheska & LY  Proofreader: Wuzimiko    QC: Roqubot
Lyrics Translator: LY, Natsu, Roqubot & Wuzimiko    Timer, Effect & Encoder: Yuuki
On the path to immortality
before a library of herbs and pills
there's far too much to take in
Just who is singing
who is hesitating
and who is standing atop the clouds?
Out of the many who have come
how many achieved the Way,
rushing to a finish?
Just who becomes anxious,
and who is carefree?
On the outside
I pretend to be weak
You don't understand,
hence you're confused
Just when, he asked,
will I achieve completion?
Could loneliness be
the secret to immortality?
Are mortals only allowed an ordinary life?
I want to cultivate as an Immortal
to remain young forever
My cultivation comes from hard work
and not from luck
I didn't come here
to sightsee
When I give it my all
it'll surpass your imagination
Even if the moon sleeps,
I will endure until sunrise
Why do I give my all?
It's all to become eternal
To prove that
even as an ordinary mortal
even when afraid,
shedding tears of fear
I can
break through
to the clear sky beyond the clouds
Reshaping my mortal body
through countless rebirths
until my primordial spirit
manifests like a blaze
and finally
harmonizing heaven and earth to become eternal
A Will Eternal
Episode 14
That's Blood Python, the familiar of Young Master Luochen.
Looks like Chen Heng made his move.
The 9th Level of Qi Condensation,
coupled with such a fearsome familiar...
if we run into them,
it'll be certain death.
9th level...
of Qi Condensation...?
With our current strength, attacking him head on would be like
throwing straw against the wind.
Looks like
we have little hope
of survival.
No.
We can't let him find us.
Let's run!
Leave us!
Senior sister,
what are you doing?
If we don't go now,
we'll really run out of time!
We can still make it!
Junior brother Bai.
Don't you understand?
Look at us.
Both Senior brother Hou and I are badly injured,
and our spiritual Qi has run dry.
In terms of speed,
we can't even outrun ordinary mortals,
let alone
Chen Heng and his men.
But
you're fast.
If you manage to get the message out,
we might have a chance
when the sect sends in reinforcements.
Quit lying to me!
I'm not a child!
I'd never ditch you guys and run on my own!
It's getting closer.
Go!
Senior sister Du...
are you insane?!
Death is inevitable at this point.
I'd rather kill myself
than die by the hands of others!
Senior sister Du!
No matter what it takes...
have you forgotten what you said?
That's right.
Hang in there, no matter what it takes.
For our sake...
you have to hang in there.
If you really want to save us,
leave right now!
You're our only hope.
Just go!
Go!
Junior sister Du.
It's the only way to
save him.
Junior brother Bai,
survive.
They move...
a lot quicker than expected.
Let's...
buy him some more time.
We'll all get through his.
I'll keep...
everyone alive...
my way!
YOUR GRANDPA BAI FROM SPIRIT STREAM SECT IS RIGHT HERE!
COME KILL ME IF YOU DARE!
WHERE IS THAT BASTARD LUOCHEN?
YOUR GRANDPA'S SICK OF WAITING!
BRING IT!
BRING IT ON!
Your Grandpa Bai from Spirit Stream Sect is right here!
Come kill me if you dare!
Bai Xiaochun...
He's luring the enemies away
to let us escape.
Why are you so silly?!
Luochen wusses,
want to kill us all?
Then come after me!
I'm over here!
I need to draw them away from the mountain.
I'LL KILL YOU ALL, NO MATTER HOW MANY!
EVEN IF I CAN'T KILL YOU ALL,
THE SPIRIT STREAM SECT WILL WIPE YOU OUT!
All disciples in the area
are to focus on killing him first.
His companions must be gravely wounded, if not dead.
They cannot get far.
Comb the area
after he's dead.
Yes,
Young Master!
So long as I keep them here,
within 16 hours,
the seniors can make it out of the mountain.
You little runt!
Die!
What tough bones.
He's almost like a beast!
Throat Crushing Grasp!
Is that all you Luochens have got?
An illusion!
I can't see my opponent at all.
I've got him cornered.
He's stuck.
You guys go search for his companions.
Damn it.
If this drags on,
it'll be dangerous for the seniors!
Caught you!
Young Master,
aside from the bodies of our people,
we found no other traces.
Although, judging from the blood on the arrows,
his injuries are deep.
He shouldn't have run far.
Quite impressive, taking a wound to close in for a kill.
I didn't think Spirit Stream Sect could produce someone like this.
Expand the search area.
He must
be captured.
Yes.
I can't wait to meet you.
He's not here.
Go!
I managed to lure them away.
The seniors
should be... safe... for now.
This place is good for hiding.
Stay alert.
Where are they hiding?
We haven't found anyone yet.
What about you?
We...
wait.
Blood traces!
Out of the forest, northeast.
Suspicious blood traces were found on the
route towards the mountain border.
Well done. Back them up immediately!
Towards the mountain border.
It's the seniors!
He's over here!
We found that brat!
The pursuers all went after junior brother Bai.
We'll need another 12 hours
to reach the border.
No.
Before sunrise,
we must reach the border of Fallen Star.
Your Grandpa is here!
Senior brother!
Luochen
We found them!
Hurry.
Leave.
So they're all here.
Might as well get rid of them all at once!
Member of Luochen
6th Level of Qi Condensation
I'M STILL ALIVE, YOU KNOW!
KEEP COMING AT ME IF YOU HAVE WHAT IT TAKES!
BRING IT!!!
KILL!!!
It took so much to capture you.
What a troublesome guy.
You're...
only at the 5th level of Qi Condensation,
yet you've killed a dozen of my men,
including Chen Yue.
Your cultivation isn't even on par with an Inner Sect disciple.
Who exactly are you?
I'm...
I'm your...
Grandpa Bai!
That's all the spiritual Qi you have left.
What a pity.
I can't die yet...!
*阎王要你三更死，谁敢留你到五更: "If the King of Hell summons you by the third watch of the night, no one would dare to keep you alive till the fifth hour". A Chinese saying describing that death is inevitable.
If the King of Hell wants you dead by midnight,
who could keep you alive till dawn?
Swirling petals dance in streams of
moonlight
The long road onward enveloped by icy mist
Is it but an illusion that setting stars lock eyes?
Life goes on as bygone dreams fade
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Pursuing my dreams alone
In wine I abandon the coming days
when reminiscing of past friends
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Smiling sheepishly as I watched the years wither away
to reveal a graying man young at heart
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Walking alone in the darkness
Only gratitude and kindness shall rest in my heart
Reflecting on a lifetime of recklessness
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Briefly, silly smiles mask the loneliness within
To where did the naive teen once dream of going?