Brought to you by Guodong Subs
This is an overlay of softsubs on a third-party video.
Please also support the official channel.
Translator: Cheska & LY    Proofreader: Wuzimiko    QC: Roqubot
Lyrics Translator: LY, Natsu, Roqubot & Wuzimiko    Timer, Effect & Encoder: Yuuki
On the path to immortality
before a library of herbs and pills
there's far too much to take in
Just who is singing
who is hesitating
and who is standing atop the clouds?
Out of the many who have come
how many achieved the Way,
rushing to a finish?
Just who becomes anxious,
and who is carefree?
On the outside
I pretend to be weak
You don't understand,
hence you're confused
Just when, he asked,
will I achieve completion?
Could loneliness be
the secret to immortality?
Are mortals only allowed an ordinary life?
I want to cultivate as an Immortal
to remain young forever
My cultivation comes from hard work
and not from luck
I didn't come here
to sightsee
When I give it my all
it'll surpass your imagination
Even if the moon sleeps,
I will endure until sunrise
Why do I give my all?
It's all to become eternal
To prove that
even as an ordinary mortal
even when afraid,
shedding tears of fear
I can
break through
to the clear sky beyond the clouds
Reshaping my mortal body
through countless rebirths
until my primordial spirit
manifests like a blaze
and finally
harmonizing heaven and earth to become eternal
A Will Eternal
Episode 12
Senior brother!
I'm fine.
Junior brother Bai.
Junior brother Bai!
Bai Xiaochun!
That was close!
Why didn't you respond earlier?!
Senior-
Senior sister, were you worried about me again?
If you died because of me, I'd feel indebted to you.
You should feel honored to become part of Luochen Clan's
spiritual sacrifice.
Stop spacing out!
Run!
Escaping by yourself again?
Or what,
let him turn us into fertilizer?
The show has just begun.
Senior sister!
Hurry!
I see a way out!
He's casting an illusory spell with the formation!
If we get entangled in fighting, we'll never escape!
I'll deal with him.
Senior brother, Fireburst Pill!
Last one!
Catch!
He's gone?
Was that an illusion too?
That's-
The monster...
finally showed itself.
How dare you stand in my way!
Take that!
Eat dirt, mop head!
I'm finally getting out of here!
Just a little more...
damn you!
It's all your fault...
that I'm stuck in this sick place!
It was an illusion!
Killing the mop head
weakened the barrier.
Could she have been a part of the formation?
Whatever,
escaping comes first!
Senior brother Hou.
Senior brother Hou!
To think that
they confined him in this demonic tree,
reduced to such a shape.
He's awake.
Senior brother.
We found you at last!
It's...
you guys.
Run!
The Luochens have defected to Blood Stream Sect.
But the formation is set.
There's nowhere to run.
No way!
Wasn't...
that guy...
Senior sister,
that way!
Keep up!
Junior brother Bai.
Do me a favor
as a sectmate!
I've finally...
gotten the perfect opportunity.
You got lucky and survived Fallen Star Forest.
This time, however,
I'm afraid you're staying here.
Don't worry,
once I get back to the sect,
I'll make sure to avenge you.
If they stay in there,
the tear is going to heal.
Feng Yan!
That sly bastard!
Trying to kill me by the hand of others?
I,
Bai Xiaochun,
will never...
die in a place like this!
These pathetic vines
can't possibly trap me!
Have a taste of the Fireburst Pill that
I prepared for Bai Xiaochun.
This...
This is...!
I-
I'm free?
Bai Xiaochun!
You're still alive?
If I'm doomed to die today,
I'm dragging you to my grave!
Be blown to pieces!
I can't believe he tried to blow me up.
Thank god for my Undying Skin.
I, Bai Xiaochun,
emerged alive!
Bai Xiaochun!
When I return to Spirit Stream Sect,
I'll make you into mincemeat!
I'm afraid you'll never make it back to your...
Spirit
Stream
Sect.
It's all because I'm useless.
It's all my fault...!
If he hadn't tried to save me,
senior brother wouldn't have...
He stopped the vines on his own
and used a spell to push me out.
To think senior brother Feng
would be so loyal and righteous.
Cheer up.
It's unwise to stay here.
Let's get going.
Chen Yue.
Please forgive me for being useless, Patriarch!
I only managed to kill one.
The other two saved the one we captured earlier
and got away.
Don't forget your role and mission.
The Great Spell of Spirit Reversal
is only half a month away from completion.
After which, our clan will break free from the shackles of fate
and be bound by no limits.
At this juncture,
we cannot afford any mistake.
Rest assured, Patriarch.
They...
will not leave Fallen Star Mountain.
I've had enough!
This Jade Slip is a piece of crap!
It doesn't respond at all.
No one would know
even if we died in here!
Can we really make it out alive?
If they stay in there,
the tear is going to heal.
Betraying our sect
is punishable by death.
Senior brother!
There's no way they will let us live.
Senior brother Feng died in there despite being
at the 7th level of Qi Condensation.
Now,
even my unique message channel is unresponsive.
Why?
Senior sister...
are you crying?
Wh-
Who's crying?
The Wind Rider perished with senior brother Feng.
With such a long way ahead,
how can we avoid being hunted?
Life sure is tough
for Bai Xiaochun!
Junior brother Bai.
You were always the most afraid of death.
Are you scared right now?
I am.
Of course I'm scared.
But the more fear I feel,
the more I want to escape
and survive.
I'm scared too.
However,
I'd rather fight it out than to be a sitting duck.
Us three
will return to the sect together.
Senior sister...
Junior sister Du.
Junior brother Bai.
After a short rest,
I managed to regain some of my powers.
Senior brother.
I'm glad you're okay.
Junior brother Bai,
long time no see.
I didn't think we'd reunite here.
Oh, Senior brother Hou!
you made Xiaomei worry every day.
This punch is from her.
Thanks for your care.
That reminds me.
This was where I found
your Voice Transmission Jade Slip.
Senior brother,
what exactly happened?
You guys must've taken the Wind Rider
and missed the villages around the Fallen Star Mountain Range.
To break free from the Sect, the Luochen Clan
set up Spiritual Restrictions
and turned to the Blood Stream Sect.
They even defied the Way,
killing innocents to harvest their breath of life.
Wherever they went,
not a soul was spared.
This...!
Spiritual power all drained.
Don't tell me...
You shouldn't have come.
If you guys haven't saved me in time,
I would've become a wronged ghost
in the Spirit Reversal Formation.
I've wasted too much of your time.
We need to go now.
Let's leave quickly.
But your injury...
Watch out!
Senior brother...
Senior sister...!
You were so hasty to leave, dear friends from Spirit Stream Sect.
I haven't fulfilled my part as the host yet.
Cut the crap.
Let's fight.
Fine.
I'll send you off then.
If you wish to seek revenge in your next life,
remember: the man who killed you
is called Chen Yue.
Junior brother Bai,
no matter what,
you must bring the news back.
Senior sister...
I'm counting on you.
Go!
He's a quick one.
I'll finish you two off
before going after him.
Bai Xiaochun,
you'd better live!
Swirling petals dance in streams of
moonlight
The long road onward enveloped by icy mist
Is it but an illusion that setting stars lock eyes?
Life goes on as bygone dreams fade
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Pursuing my dreams alone
In wine I abandon the coming days
when reminiscing of past friends
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Smiling sheepishly as I watched the years wither away
to reveal a graying man young at heart
Emotion shapes the mortal realm
where crystal voices sing of gnawing pains
Walking alone in the darkness
Only gratitude and kindness shall rest in my heart
Reflecting on a lifetime of recklessness
Lamenting that swords mean nothing in the way of feelings
Briefly, silly smiles mask the loneliness within
To where did the naive teen once dream of going?