Brought to you by Guodong Subs
Translator: Wuzimiko    Proofreader: K     QC: Raliath
Lyrics Translator: Wuzimiko     Timer & Effects: Yuuki
There are some things
I must tell you.
Over these years,
I've forgotten a lot of things.
My memory
has been failing.
A lot of things,
I'll forget if I didn't write them down.
That is the after effect of using such a power.
I don't know
if you're also affected by it.
Since you carry
a strange energy
similar to this.
Adapted from novel of the same name, "The Grave Robbers' Chronicles (Dao Mu Bi Ji): Bronze Tree of Death" by Nanpai Sanshu
Original work by Nanpai Sanshu
Chief Producer: Cheng Wu
Producer: Zou Zhengyu
The Grave Robbers' Chronicles  (Dao Mu Bi Ji): Bronze Tree of Death
An endless road ahead.
Two extremities of love and loyalty.
Inner demons shrouding the heart --
they wallow in the past.
Where is my old friend?
He is lingering in the shadows.
Convinced that he hasn't veered too far off course, in this world of fleeting destinies.
Why do you pine? Why do you yearn?
Wishing to turn back, yet it was a path of no return.
The way of life is vicious, we keep going in circles.
Hard to discern truths from lies,
to tell the evil from the kind.
In front of my eyes, a bungling mess of mountains and waters.
Why do you tread a path this treacherous?
Embroiled in sinister schemes, in trepidation as the tables turn and turn.
I bid you adieu --
shall we never meet again!
Episode 01
Oh, my!
Today's our lucky day!
Cut the crap.
If not for me keeping an eye out,
you'd have gotten caught today!
With my skills,
that'd be impossible.
Ha! Your skill...
What about my skill?
Okay, okay, that's enough.
We've got quite a haul today.
We'll have a feast in *Lou Wai Lou.
楼外楼 (Lou Wai Lou): an extremely famous traditional restaurant in Hangzhou, China.
Ohh,
this looks interesting.
(Certificate of Release
No. 0-0487
Male, Hometown: Jiangsu)
What a surprise.
We even stole from an ex-convict!
This guy...
could he also be a pickpocket?
Those in the same line are also often enemies.
The net of law has large meshes,
but it lets nothing through.
Reaching for pockets may thrill you for a minute,
but it sure
s-saddens your family for a long time.
Young man.
You learned well in prison.
However, reciting slogans
is pretty much useless.
Hah!
You guys...
had b-better turn over a new leaf.
Wu Mountain House
(Wu Xie's Antique Shop)
Hello?
Who's this?
Hello.
It's me.
Don't tell me y-you've forgotten my voice?
Lao Yang (Old Yang)!
You rascal.
I haven't heard you speak in three years!
Of course I can't recognize your voice.
You sound all g-grown up now!
And you still dare to call me?
You haven't contacted me at all over the years.
I thought you were dead!
Are you free tonight?
Let's eat out.
I haven't ate a decent piece of meat in three years.
Today,
I must have my fill!
Sure!
To celebrate your return.
See you at Luo Wai Lou.
Yeah.
Bye bye!
Lao Yang.
Lao Yang!
Come on, Lao Wu (Old Wu), bottoms up!
You even put on weight!
Screw you.
In there and out here are like two different worlds.
Count your blessings that you could see me again.
What exactly were you meddling in?
I heard your cousin's still in prison.
Stop bringing it up.
He's the one who dragged me into trouble.
He found something precious and just couldn't keep his mouth shut.
He even confessed to his past atrocities!
Something precious?
What do you mean?
That thing is really eerie.
You wouldn't k-know
even if I told you.
We practically grew up sharing pants.
Don't you know my family?
I learned well from my grandpa.
So long as you tell me the shape.
Have you seen this?
For the past three years...
your drawing skills haven't improved one bit.
Two branches,
and a stroke.
Is this a pattern?
Why does your drawing look like a tree?
What the heck is this?
You don't say.
It is a tree branch.
A bronze branch
as t-thick as your wrist.
At that time,
I was convinced by my cousin's boasting and
went deep into the Qinling Mountains.
We trekked for more than a dozen days.
Apart from the layer after layer of old-growth forest,
we found nothing.
Just when we were about to give up,
something different appeared in front of us.
The geographical environment in there
is very unique.
It was filled with massive banyan trees that can hardly be hugged by ten men.
In that forest,
tree roots crawled all over the forest floor
and there was no way to walk normally.
Stone figures?
As the saying goes,
where bamboos don't survive lands saline,
where bridges of offerings sprout overnight;
where mountains look all brown and dry,
it is worth panning the sand and soil.
In such places with abnormal vegetation growth,
something must exist.
So we followed the leads of the stone men
and continued to go deeper.
As we walked,
an ancient path appeared.
While we were inside,
we walked for hours.
The deeper we delved, the thicker the aerial roots.
In the end...
That structure
was like a pyramid planted upside down.
The slopes on all four sides of the pit
were carved into stairs.
There were more than a hundred steps.
By the time we reached the bottom,
it was already midnight.
However, it wasn't an ancient tomb.
More like,
a sacrificial altar.
The mud well in the middle
is around a dozen meters deep.
Pointing our torchlight into the well,
we saw nothing but grass.
As for what's in it,
you can guess.
If it really is a sacrificial altar,
there must be sacrifices.
There must be something under the altar.
I'm impressed!
I silently thought of everything
I could think of.
However, it turned out
to be way more shocking
that I expected.
My cousin and I took turns digging.
15 meters in, and we
still haven't struck the bottom.
Who knows how deep is that thing?
At the end of the day,
apart from some broken jade tiles and earthenware,
there was nothing.
The two of us were beyond exhausted.
According to my cousin,
we've seen pretty much.
We might as well leave.
However,
I couldn't swallow it.
As if I had been taken over,
I just wanted to keep digging.
I have a strong feeling
that there must be
a secret hidden underneath.
That sound...
it was as if it came from hell.
It was chilling.
Are they really bronze wares?
Of course!
It's like what I drew you just now.
What a pity.
We did a rough calculation.
That part of the bronze tree branch that was buried underground
would go down for around ten more meters.
That thing must at least be 30 meters.
Something that gigantic
must require more than ten thousand men to build.
Keep spinning.
How can there be a vessel that huge?
That's because you haven't seen anything.
Tch.
Since you took nothing, why were you jailed for three years?
I guess I didn't exactly take nothing.
Look at this.
How's this?
This thing...
where did you get it?
L-Let go first!
Let go first!
I-I'm gonna get mad if you pull it again!
That hurts!
You didn't go easy on me at all.
There's no need to react like that even when you see something good.
Spill it!
What's with that thing?
Where did you get it?
Bet you've never seen it.
You'll be green with envy once you knew.
This thing
was taken from a zombie
in the sacrificial pit.
Zombie?
It turned up by accident
when I was digging that pit.
That zombie was tightly bound by rattan ropes, like a cocoon.
It was probably
a human sacrifice of a higher status.
This thing
was on that zombie's earlobe.
I took it since it looked good.
What do you think?
Green tinged with black.
This must be a first.
What's with that expression?
Why are you so uptight?
Don't tell me there is something more to it?
Are you really jealous?
You don't understand.
This bell...
I've seen it in somewhere else.
The hexagonal bell.
It's s-s-something this menacing?
I've seen it in the Seven-Star Palace and the undersea tomb.
It's a very creepy bell.
Once it rings,
it can hypnotize anyone who hears it.
However,
you look fine wearing it on your ear.
My goodness.
And I thought the sacrificial altar was enough for me to boast for a lifetime.
Compared to your adventures,
mine are absolutely pathetic.
If you like it,
I'll give it to you.
Hey!
No wonder you're fine.
It's been filled with rosin.
It can't ring anymore.
However, its better for people
to keep their distance from this sort of thing.
But you're not just anyone.
Don't I know you?
You're more curious than anyone.
If you're interested,
let's visit that place again.
I made a mark at that place.
There might be more of these bells.
Give me a break.
You've learned nothing in jail.
Re-offending warrants a harsher sentence.
You might get executed for it.
Idiot.
Don't run!
Stop right there!
What's with that one-track mind?
Just tell me if you're low on cash.
I can give it to you, brother.
Har har.
When we were young, you'd ask for interest even over an ice pop.
You still remember? That was so long ago.
What happened during childhood
can affect someone throughout their lives.
You're not entirely blameless for how I am today.
I didn't tell you to rob graves.
How is it my fault when you're the one who decided to go astray?
You are indeed part of the reason.
Do you remember?
You used to always tell me stories about your grandpa.
You even flaunted his treasures to me.
I was tempted back then.
I thought,
if I have the chance,
I must go on an adventure.
That would make my life worthwhile.
Frankly speaking,
in the past three years,
I think of that place everyday.
I just couldn't take it lying down.
Stop bullsh*tting me.
I never told my stories to that cousin of yours.
You can cut that melancholic act.
Can't I act melancholic when we're already at the West Lake?
Where's your conscience?
I'm telling the truth.
First of all,
I'm just curious to see it again.
Secondly,
*Uncle Three: Wu Xie's third uncle.
didn't you say your *Uncle Three went missing?
Since they have the same bell,
there might be fresh clues over there.
T/N: from the second volume "Angry Sea, Hidden Sands". As Chinese can be read from both left to right and right to left, the message was meant to be intentionally confusing.
(Wu Sanxing)
(Caused me)
(Caused me to Die a Horrible Death)
(Xie Lianhuan)
Uncle Three.
Hey,
are you listening to me?
Lao Wu.
You count yourself as my brother?
You're the one who said you want to find your Uncle Three.
Also,
w-what's the big deal making the trip with me?
Will I harm you?
Just because you know some geomancy, y-y-you...
I'll go with you.
But I'll say this first.
You are not allowed to take anything.
Also,
give me that bell.
Still putting on that tough act?
Hey! What are you doing?!
I bet you wanted to go from the start!
Do you want to die?
Lao Wu!
You'd better honor your words!
Hey!
Come over here!
That's unfair!
Look! An a-a-airplane!
I say,
couldn't we have just taken a flight?
The road was so bumpy.
Isn't this because of you?
You've just been freed a few days ago, and you're already running around with a huge backpack.
What if you get checked?
You're exaggerating.
With your looks, anyone could recognize you from a mile away.
I can't deny.
Time has
drowned out even the claps of thunder.
They scatter
the cut-up pieces of myself.
I can only fumble around, trying to piece them back.
Why must I climb mountains and peaks
to collect,
but I seem to be late every time,
tracks of hanging onto someone.
Those places I once trodden,
how did they
look like originally?
Trying to trace those footsteps behind me,
I have forgotten;
the path I came from was too far and too long.
Where would be the end of my journey?
Where would it be?
Where would it be...